Preliminary Inventory of the Latviesu Centrala Komiteja Records
Hoover Institution Archives
- Orders, reports, and other records relating to Latvian police and military units, 1941-1945 (Box 98)
  - Headquarters, Latvian Police Reinforcement Units, 1945 (Folder 105: 6)
  - 15th Battalion, 3rd Recovery Company, 1945 (Box-folder 106: 1)
  - Latvian Police, 1st Training Battalion, 1943 (Folder 106: 2)
  - Latvian Police, 2nd Training Battalion, 1943 (Folder 106: 3)
  - Liepaja Police Regiment, 1944 (Folder 106: 4)
  - Casualty reports, 2nd Latvian Police Regiment, 1944 (Folder 106: 5)
  - 3rd Latvian Police Regiment, 1944 (Folder 106: 6)
  - Conscription lists, 1944 (Box 107)
    - Jelgava (Folder 107: 1-5)
    - Bauska (Folder 107: 6)
    - Tukums (Folder 107: 7)
    - Jekabpils (Folder 107: 8)
  - Latvian Police Liaison Officer (Box 108)
    - 1943 (Folder 108: 1-4)
    - 1943 (Box-folder 109: 1-2)
    - 1944 (Folder 109: 3-5)
    - 1944 (Box-folder 110: 1-4)
  - 266th E. Battalion, 1944 (Folder 111: 1-4)
- Records of the Latviesu Centrala Komiteja in Germany, 1945-1947 (Box 112)
  - General file, 1945-1946 (Folder 112: 1-4)
  - Administrative and legal files, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 113: 1-3)
  - Food supply file, 1945-1946 (Folder 113: 4)
  - Housing file, 1945-1946 (Folder 113: 5)
  - Employment file, 1945-1946 (Folder 113: 6)
  - District committee file, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 114: 1-3)
  - General file, 1947 (Folder 114: 4)
- Records of the Latvian National Committee, Potsdam, Germany, 1944-1945
  - Legislative file, 1944-1945 (Folder 114: 5)
  - Financial file, 1945 (Box-folder 115: 1)
  - Memoranda and resolutions concerning the status of the Baltic states, 1945-1946 (Folder 115: 2)
  - Correspondence with Allied military authorities, 1945-1947 (Folder 115: 3)
  - Correspondence with British occupation authorities, 1945 (Folder 115: 4)
  - POW file, 1945-1946 (Folder 115: 5)
  - Correspondence between Janis Meizis and Karlis Zarins, 1945-1948. (Folder 115: 6)
    Includes supplementary materials
- Records of the 1st Latvian District Committee, Lubeck, Germany, 1945-1947 (Box 116)
  - Correspondence, minutes of meetings, and materials relating to the election of committee members, 1945-1947 (Folder 116: 1)
  - Directives and other materials concerning the status of displaced persons, 1945-1947 (Folder 116: 2)
  - Financial records, 1946 (Folder 116: 3)
  - Welfare officer's file, 1946 (Folder 116: 4)
- Publications of the Latvian State Bureau of Statistics, 1931-1940 (Box 117)
  - Pilsetu pasvaldibu finanses 1920.-1930., 1931 (Folder 117: 1)
  - Financu statistika 1935., 1935 (Folder 117: 2)
  - Financu un kredita statistika 1936., 1936 (Folder 117: 3)
  - Financu un kredita statistika 1938. g., 1938 (Folder 117: 4)
  - Financu un kredita statistika 1939. g., 1939 (Folder 117: 5)
  - Pilsetu gruntsgabali un dzivokli, 1936 (Folder 117: 6)
  - Darba statistika 1934. g., 1935 (Folder 117: 7)
  - Darba statistika 1935. g., 1936 (Folder 117: 8)
  - Darba statistika 1936. g., 1937 (Folder 117: 9)
  - Pirma tirdzniecibas skaitisana Latvija 1935. gada., 1938 (Box-folder 118: 1)
  - Tirdzniecibas uznemumu apgrozijumi 1933.-1935. gadam., 1937 (Folder 118: 2)
  - Latvijas amatnieciba un rupnieciba 1935. g., 1938 (Folder 118: 3)
  - Latvijas areja tirdznieciba un transits 1936, 1937 (Folder 118: 4)
  - Latvjias areja tirdznieciba un transits 1938, 1939 (Folder 118: 5)
  - Rupniecibas statistika 1936, 1938 (Folder 118: 6)
  - Rupniecibas statistika 1937, 1939 (Folder 118: 7)
  - Rupniecibas statistika 1938, 1940 (Folder 118: 8)
- Photographs depicting life in Latvian displaced person camps in Germany, 1945-1947 (Box 119)
  - Memmingen camp, 1947 (Folder 119: 1)
  - Hochfeld camp, 1946-1947 (Folder 119: 2-5)
  - Hochfeld and Augsburg camps, 1946 (Folder 119: 6-7)
  - Augsburg camp, 1946 (Folder 119: 8)
  - Murnau camp, 1948 (Folder 119: 9)
  - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Folder 119: 10)
  - Greven camp, 1946-1947 (Folder 119: 11)
  - Greven camp, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 120: 1-2)
  - Miscellaneous negatives, n.d. (Folder 120: 3)
  - Art school, Esslingen camp, 1946 (Folder 120: 4)
  - Workshops, Esslingen camp, 1946 (Folder 120: 5)
  - Drama school, Esslingen camp, 1946 (Folder 120: 6)
  - Baltic Olympiad sports event, Augsburg, 1946 (Folder 120: 7)
  - Song festival, Fischbach camp, 1947 (Box-folder 121: 1)
  - Song festival, Ansbach camp, 1946 (Folder 121: 2)
  - Augsburg camp, 1946 (Folder 121: 3-4)
  - Esslingen camp, 1946 (Folder 121: 5)
  - Kleinkotz camp, 1947 (Folder 121: 6)
- Casualty reports and other records relating to Latvian policemen and soldiers in World War II, 1942-1944 (Box 122)
  - Correspondence, cemetery plans, and names of the dead, largely in relation to fighting on the Eastern Front, 1942-1944 (Folder 122: 1)
  - Death records, including accompanying correspondence, concerning Latvian policemen and soldiers, 1942-1944 (Folder 122: 2-5)
  - Death records, including accompanying correspondence, concerning Latvian policemen and soldiers, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 123: 1-3)
  - Lists of missing and fallen soldiers, 1942-1944 (Folder 123: 4-5)
  - Miscellaneous records concerning dead and missing soldiers, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 124: 1)
  - Lists of those killed in action, 1942-1944 (Folder 124: 2-5)
  - Lists of those killed in action, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 125: 1-2)
  - Photographs of military cemeteries, n.d. (Folder 125: 3)
- Orders, reports, and other records relating to Latvian police and military units, 1942-1944
  - 17th E Battalion, 1942 (Folder 125: 4)
  - Riga Police Headquarters, 1942 (Folder 125: 5)
  - 270th Abrene Pioneer Battalion, 1942 (Folder 125: 6)
  - 313th Latvian Police Battalion, 1944 (Folder 125: 7)
  - 16th Zemgale Battalion, 1943 (Folder 125: 8)
  - 17th Vidzeme Battalion, 1943 (Folder 125: 9)
  - 18th Kurzeme Battalion, 1943 (Folder 125: 10)
  - 19th Latgale Battalion, 1943 (Box-folder 126: 1)
  - 22nd Daugava Battalion, 1943-1944 (Folder 126: 2)
  - 23rd Gauja Battalion, 1943 (Folder 126: 3)
  - Liaison Officer to Chief of Police and SS, 1943 (Folder 126: 4)
  - 266th E Battalion (Folder 126: 5-6)
  - 268th Ergli Battalion, 1943 (Folder 126: 7)
  - 279th Cesis Battalion, 1943 (Folder 126: 8)
  - 279th (271st Aizpute) Battalion, 1943 (Folder 126: 9)
  - Recovery Company, 1944 (Box-folder 127: 1)
  - 16th E Battalion, 1942 (Folder 127: 2)
  - 23rd Battalion, 1944 (Folder 127: 3)
  - 25th Abava Battalion, 1942 (Folder 127: 4)
  - 267th Reserve Battalion, 1943 (Folder 127: 5)
  - 271st Battalion, 1944 (Folder 127: 6)
  - 313th Police Battalion, 1943 (Folder 127: 7)
  - Riga Police Regiment, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 128: 1-2)
  - 2nd Headquarters Liaison Unit, 1944 (Folder 128: 3)
  - 3rd Latvian Police Regiment, 1944 (Folder 128: 4)
  - Kurzeme Police Regiment, 3rd Battalion, 1944 (Folder 128: 5)
  - 20th Riga Police Battalion, 1944 (Folder 128: 6-7)
  - 21st Liepaja Battalion, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 129: 1)
  - 22nd Battalion, 1944 (Folder 129: 2)
  - 25th Abava Battalion, 1944 (Folder 129: 3)
  - 276th Kuldiga Battalion, 1943 (Folder 129: 4-5)
  - Names of soldiers killed in action, various units, 1942-1944 (Folder 129: 6)
  - 266th E Battalion, 1942 (Box-folder 130: 1-2)
  - 313th Police Battalion, 1944 (Folder 130: 3)
  - 317th Battalion, 1943-1944 (Folder 130: 4)
  - 672nd Battalion, 1944 (Folder 130: 5)
  - 18th E Ergli Battalion, 1942 (Folder 130: 6)
  - 271st Aizpute Battalion, 1942 (Box-folder 131: 1)
  - 273rd Battalion, 1942 (Folder 131: 2)
  - 280th Battalion, 1943 (Folder 131: 3)
  - 281st Battalion, 1943 (Folder 131: 4-5)
  - 27th Burtnieki Battalion, 1943 (Folder 131: 6)
  - 20th Riga Police Battalion, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 132: 1-2)
  - 26th Tukums Battalion, 1943 (Folder 132: 3)
  - 319th F Battalion, 1943 (Folder 132: 4-5)
  - 322nd Battalion, 1944 (Folder 132: 6)
  - 316th (280th b) Battalion, 1943 (Box-folder 133: 1)
  - 282nd Venta Battalion, 1943 (Folder 133: 2)
  - 19th Latgale Battalion, 1942 (Folder 133: 3)
  - 25th Abava Battalion, 1943 (Folder 133: 4)
  - 321st F Battalion, 1944 (Folder 133: 5)
  - 270th (672nd) Abrene Pioneer Battalion, 1943 (Box-folder 134: 1)
  - 24th Talsi Battalion, 1943 (Folder 134: 2)
  - 316th Battalion, 1944 (Folder 134: 3)
  - 277th Sigulda Battalion, 1942-1943 (Folder 134: 4)
- Records of the delegation of the Latviesu Centrala Komiteja in the American zone of occupation in Germany, 1946-1947
  - Minutes of meetings, 1946-1947 (Folder 134: 5)
  - Correspondence with headquarters, 1946 (Folder 134: 6-7)
  - General correspondence, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 135: 1-2)
  - Correspondence with local representatives, 1946-1947 (Folder 135: 3-4)
- Records of the Latvian Central Council in Germany, 1945-1948. (Box 136)
  Minutes of meetings
  - First session, Hiddessen, 1945 (Folder 136: 1)
  - Second session, Hanau, 1946 (Folder 136: 2)
  - Third session, Wurzburg, 1946 (Folder 136: 3)
  - Fourth session, Blomberg, 1946 (Folder 136: 4)
  - Fifth session, Hanau, 1946 (Folder 136: 5)
  - Sixth session, Kassel, 1946 (Folder 136: 6)
  - Seventh session, Meerbeck, 1947 (Box-folder 137: 1-2)
  - Eighth session, Darmstadt, 1947 (Folder 137: 3-4)
  - Ninth session, Fischbach, 1947 (Folder 137: 5-6)
  - Tenth session, Babenhausen, 1948 (Box-folder 138: 1-2)
  - Eleventh session, Wurzburg, 1948 (Folder 138: 3-4)
  - Twelfth session, Hanau, 1948 (Box-folder 139: 1)
  - Thirteenth session, Fulda, 1948 (Folder 139: 2)
- Records of the Latvian National Committee and other organizations in Germany, 1944-1946
  - Ledger, 1945 (Folder 139: 3)
  - Record of budget expenditures, 1945 (Folder 139: 4)
  - Accounts, 1945 (Folder 139: 5-7)
  - Record of deposits, 1945 (Folder 139: 8)
  - Miscellaneous financial records, 1945 (Box-folder 140: 1-4)
  - Income and expenditure records, 1946 (Folder 140: 5)
  - Accounts and correspondence, 1946 (Folder 140: 6)
  - Personnel records, Lubeck, 1946 (Folder 140: 7)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1946 (Box-folder 141: 1)
  - Financial records of 1st Latvian District Committee, 1946 (Folder 141: 2)
  - Minutes of meetings, 1945-1946 (Folder 141: 3)
  - Instructions, notices, and orders of the president of the Latvian National Committee, 1945 (Folder 141: 4)
  - Decrees of the president of the Latvian National Committee, 1945 (Folder 141: 5)
  - Surveys of activities, 1945 (Folder 141: 6)
  - Organizational file, 1945-1946. (Folder 141: 7)
    Includes information on wages and salaries
  - File on benefits and pensions, 1945 (Folder 141: 8)
  - Reports on conditions in displaced person camps, 1945 (Folder 141: 9)
  - Correspondence with Latviesu Centrala Komiteja, 1945 (Folder 141: 10)
  - Correspondence with Latvijas Veselibas Kamera, 1945 (Folder 141: 11)
  - Correspondence with Latvian Red Cross, 1945 (Folder 141: 12)
  - Correspondence concerning the Latvian War Hospital in Schwerin, 1945 (Folder 141: 13)
  - Community court file, 1945 (Folder 141: 14)
  - General file, 1944-1945 (Folder 141: 15)
  - File on Latvian prisoners of war, 1944-1945 (Folder 142: 1)
  - File on closing of Latvian police headquarters, 1945 (Folder 142: 2)
  - Materials relating to Latvian prisoners of war in Putlos, 1944-1945 (Folder 142: 3-4)
  - Correspondence with British military authorities, 1945 (Folder 142: 5)
  - Correspondence with 626 Military Government Detachment, 1946 (Folder 142: 6)
  - Instructions and orders issued by 626 Military Government Detachment, 1946 (Box-folder 143: 1)
  - Correspondence with the United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (UNRRA), 1946 (Folder 143: 2)
  - Property claims file, 1945 (Folder 143: 3)
  - Financial records of the 1st Latvian District Committee, 1946 (Folder 143: 4)
  - General file of the Latvian Agricultural Training School in Alt-Erfrade, 1946-1947 (Folder 143: 5)
- Records of the Latvian Representation at Detmold, Germany, 1945-1948 (Box 144)
  - General file, 1946-1947 (Folder 144: 1)
  - Financial records, 1945-1946 (Folder 144: 2-3)
  - Minutes of teachers' meetings, 1946-1947 (Folder 144: 4)
  - Duplicates of school certificates, 1947-1948 (Folder 144: 5)
- Music compositions by Janis Zvaigzne, 1944 (Box 145)
  - "Andante religioso" (Folder 145: 1)
  - "Kareivju klubina" (Folder 145: 2)
  - "Valse con calore" (Folder 145: 3)
  - "Vejiem lidz!" (Folder 145: 4)
  - "Izluku patrula" (Folder 145: 5)
  - "Divi marsi" (Folder 145: 6)
- Records pertaining to Latvian police forces, 1944-1945
  - General file of the headquarters for the liquidation of police operations, 1944-1945 (Folder 145: 7-9)
  - Correspondence file of the headquarters for the liquidation of police operations, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 146: 1-2)
  - Correspondence concerning the tracing of relatives, 1944-1945 (Folder 146: 3-4)
  - Personnel file, 1944-1945 (Folder 146: 5)
  - Materials relating to the evacuation of a hospital in Riga, 1944-1945 (Folder 146: 6)
  - Names of dismissed employees, 1945 (Box-folder 147: 1)
  - Personnel file, 1944-1945 (Folder 147: 2)
  - Materials relating to the arrival of employees in Germany, 1944-1945 (Folder 147: 3-4)
  - Materials relating to the issuance of food coupons, 1944 (Folder 147: 5)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence and personnel files, 1944-1945 (Folder 147: 6)
  - Reports from district police chiefs, 1944-1945 (Folder 147: 7-8)
  - Materials relating to the liquidation of police operations, 1944-1945
    - Valmiera District (Folder 147: 9)
    - Valka District (Folder 147: 10)
    - Rezekne District (Box-folder 148: 1)
    - Jelgava District (Folder 148: 2)
    - Madona District (Folder 148: 3)
    - Ludza District (Folder 148: 4)
    - Jekabpils District (Folder 148: 5)
    - Ilukste District (Folder 148: 6)
    - Daugavpils District (Folder 148: 7-8)
    - Cesis District (Box-folder 149: 1)
    - Bauska District (Folder 149: 2)
    - Abrene District (Folder 149: 3)
    - Railway police (Folder 149: 4)
    - Riga District (Folder 149: 5-7)
- Four motion picture reels, largely depicting scenes of life in displaced person camps in Germany (Film-shelf Film shelf)
- Four reels of microfilm (Microfilm-cabinet Microfilm cabinet)